A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Business Interests, Series C FA312
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Standard Oil Companies
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Profit Sharing Plan, 1899-1930 (Box 133, Folder 987)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. comments on Executive Profit-Sharing Plan.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Mission Corporation Stock, 1935 (Box 133, Folder 988)
    Sale of stock received from Standard Oil of New Jersey.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Dinner for Retiring Members, 1933 (Box 133, Folder 989)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. participation.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Stock Acquisition Plan, 1926-1936 (Box 133, Folder 990)
    Copies of plan; purchase charts.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Company Conditions, 1921-1929 (Box 133, Folder 991)
    Teagle-John D. Rockefeller, Jr. correspondence re length of work day.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Walter Styer, 1938-1944 (Box 133, Folder 992)
    Dissatisfied employee's complaints.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Fortune Article, 1934-1940 (Box 133, Folder 993)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller comments on first draft.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Charles T. White, 1930-1941 (Box 133, Folder 994)
    John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. letters re White's 40-year service button, retirement. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. personal gifts to him. White's plans to write biography of Standard Oil of New Jersey directors for company use; his work with Nevins. Charts on the original stockholders of Standard Oil of Ohio. White's death.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Bayonne Housing, 1919-1934 (Box 133, Folder 995)
    Selection of A. J. Thomas as architect; rising prises; construction; rent rates. Return on investment; difficulties in renting apartments. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. support of project; publication of description booklet. Sale by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Dissolution of cooperative. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., C. J. Hicks.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Bayonne Housing, 1928-1943 (Box 133, Folder 996)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Bayonne Housing - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA), Bayonne, 1917-1931 (Box 133, Folder 997)
    John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. spoke at opening.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Bayonne Housing - Re New Jersey Tenement Law, 1923-1927 (Box 133, Folder 998)
    Successful lobbying for state law permitting 8 foot ceiling.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Bayonne Housing - Additional Land Purchase, 1923-1927 (Box 133, Folder 999)
    Purchased to protect apartments owned by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Bayonne Housing - Stock Purchase, 1918-1933 (Box 133, Folder 1000)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. investment in Bayonne Housing Association.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Bayonne - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Lots, 1935-1946 (Box 134, Folder 1001)
    Disposition of extra Bayonne property not needed for housing development. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Thomas M. Debevoise, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Bayonne - Taxes, 1932-1942 (Box 134, Folder 1002)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - 7% Preferred Stock, 1919-1928 (Box 134, Folder 1003)
    Issued in 1919; family investment policies worked out in terms of this stock. 1926, Stock redeemed by debentures; Rockefeller participation. John D. Rockefeller's syndicate participation, profit, gift of profit to Funds. Correspondents include Bertram Cutler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Jersey Standard Club, 1923-1942 (Box 134, Folder 1004)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1923 radio address on "Principle of Service" delivered at 26 Broadway Club dinner; 1927 talk on "Character". John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller named honorary members. Copy of George Jones' 1927 address. John D. Rockefeller messages to Annual Dinners. Club's name changed to Jersey Standard. 1936, Nelson A. Rockefeller attended dinner, joined Club. Re Executive Golf Tournament. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, E. B. Lymen.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - The Lamp - Miscellaneous Issues (Box 134, Folder 1004A)
    Includes 75th Anniversary of Jersey Standard.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Synthetic Rubber, 1942 (Box 134, Folder 1005)
    Investigation of relations between Standard Oil of New Jersey and the German firm, I. G. Farben. Standard Oil purchased rights to synthetic rubber patents, 1929; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. supported company's position when committee charged that Standard Oil created rubber shortage by failing to build synthetic plants - virtual treason. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise.
    87.1S9a
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Synthetic Rubber - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Mr. Farish, 1942 (Box 134, Folder 1006)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Synthetic Rubber - Re P.M. Clippings, 1942 (Box 134, Folder 1007)
    PM clippings demanding John D. Rockefeller, Jr. remove Standard Oil officials. Editor's pressure tactics against John D. Rockefeller, Jr., his response; Marshall Field's involvement.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Synthetic Rubber - Letters of Criticism and Miscellaneous Letters, 1942 (Box 134, Folder 1008)
    Outright condemnations and requests for "the other side of the story." Thomas M. Debevoise's answers.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Synthetic Rubber - Clippings, 1942-1943 (Box 135, Folder 1009)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New Jersey - Rubber Patents - Printed Material, 1942-1943 (Box 135, Folder 1010)
    87.1S9a1
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New York, 1923-1939 (Box 135, Folder 1011)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. urges employee representation. Stock exchanges; proxies; sale of stock. Discussion of annuity plans; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. letters to retiring officers. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Bertram Cutler.
    87.1S91
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New York - Merger of Standard Oil and Vacuum Company, 1930-1931 (Box 135, Folder 1012)
    Court order approving merger.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New York - New Jersey Property, 1923-1942 (Box 136, Folder 1013)
    Storage facilities at Palisades; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s objections; company promises.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of New York - Chas M. Higgins, 1928-1937 (Box 136, Folder 1014)
    Tributes after 58 years service.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Ohio, 1937-1967 (Box 136, Folder 1015)
    Friendly sentiments to company officers; old employees' requests for aid. Information on history of company. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, W. T. Holliday, Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    87.1S10
  - Standard Oil Companies - Union Tank Car Company, 1914-1956 (Box 136, Folder 1016)
    Information on company; gift of playing cards to Rockefellers. Letters from stockholders and old employees. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Robert W. Gumbel.
    87.1U
  - Standard Oil Companies - Vacuum Oil Company, 1921-1931 (Box 136, Folder 1017)
    Christmas greetings; appeals from employees; stock shifts. Merger with Standard Oil of New York. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Bertram Cutler.
    87.1V
  - Standard Oil Companies - Venezuela Syndicate, Inc., 1939-1949 (Box 136, Folder 1018)
    Mary Clark Rockefeller (Mrs. Nelson A. Rockefeller) interested in Syndicate. Rapid return on investment; profits invested in other stocks. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Bertram Cutler, Mary Clark Rockefeller.
    87.1V2
  - Standard Oil Companies - Waters-Pierce Company, 1911-1913 (Box 136, Folder 1019)
    Waters-Pierce Suit; control of Waters-Pierce after dissolution of Standard Oil of New Jersey. Proxy fight; incomplete; effectiveness of dissolution of Standard Oil of New Jersey the real issue. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller.
    87.1W1
  - Standard Oil Companies - Socony Vacuum Company, 1932-1939 (Box 137, Folder 1020)
    Thomas M. Debevoise and G. P. Whaley work behind Socony management protecting stockholders interests. Requests for assistance from company directed through John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, both from employees and prospective suppliers. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, G. P. Whaley.
    87.2
  - Standard Oil Companies - Socony Vacuum Company, 1940-1947 (Box 137, Folder 1021)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Socony Vacuum Company, 1942-1961 (Box 137, Folder 1022)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil Company - Employees, 1923-1938 (Box 138, Folder 1027)
    Appeals for help.
    87.3
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil Company - Employees, 1935-1959 (Box 138, Folder 1028)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil Company - Advertising, 1915-1935 (Box 138, Folder 1029)
    Requests for Standard Oil advertising placed with Rockefellers. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Ivy Lee, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    87.4
  - Standard Oil Companies - House Resolution #59, 1932 (Box 138, Folder 1030)
    Sam Rayburn requested information on Standard Oil stock holdings from John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s nominees. No information here.
- Turck and Company - Special Services
  - Turck and Company - Special Work - Corporate Research, Inc. - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1939-1942 (Box 137, Folder 1023)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller retained company to do investment research for him.
    216
  - Turck and Company - Special Work - Corporate Research, Inc. - John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1939-1942 (Box 137, Folder 1024)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. payments to corporation for services rendered.
  - Turck and Company - Special Work - Corporate Research, Inc. - Meeting Minutes, 1933-1942 (Box 137, Folder 1025)
  - Turck and Company - Special Work - Corporate Research, Inc., 1931-1947 (Box 138, Folder 1026)
    Organized by Nelson A. Rockefeller, Fenton Turck and Webster Todd as a service corporation in marketing and distributing merchandise. 1933, Nelson A. Rockefeller bought out partners, changed name to Special Work. Company worked closely with Rockefeller Center, Inc. renting office. Name changed again to Corporate Research, Inc. Dissolved in 1942. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Turck and Company - Special Work - Turck Company Inc., 1932-1941 (Box 139, Folder 1032A)
- United States Steel Corporation (U.S. Steel)
  - United States Steel Corporation - By Laws, Legal Papers, Incorporation, 1901-1911 (Box 139, Folder 1031)
    Correspondence re purchase of Rockefeller Minnesota iron interests by United States Steel Company. John D. Rockefeller resigns from Board; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. elected; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. resignation. Rockefeller defense in 1911 Steel Trust case; Frederick T. Gates-Starr J. Murphy discussion of Lamar. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller, Frederick T. Gates, G. W. Murray, Starr J. Murphy.
  - United States Steel Corporation - By Laws, Legal Papers, Incorporation, 1901-1920 (Box 139, Folder 1032)